[
    {
    "question": " Which of the following is NOT a valid deadlock prevention scheme? (GATE CSE CS 2000)",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " Release all resources before requesting a new resource",
        " Number the resources uniquely and never request a lower numbered resource than the last one requested."
        ," Never request a resource after releasing any resource."
        ," Request and all required resources be allocated before execution."
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "GENERAL Operating Systems",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},
{
    "question": " A graphics card has on board memory of 1 MB. Which of the following modes can the card not support? (GATE CSE CS 2000)",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " 1600 x 400 resolution with 256 colours on a 17 inch monitor",
        " 1600 x 400 resolution with 16 million colours on a 14 inch monitor",
        " 800 x 400 resolution with 16 million colours on a 17 inch monitor",
        " 800 x 800 resolution with 256 colours on a 14 inch monitor"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "Monitor size doesn’t matter here. So, we can easily deduce that answer should be (b) as this has the highest memory requirements. Let us verify it. Number of bits required to store a 16M colors pixel = ceil(log2(16*1000000)) = 24 \n Number of bytes required for 1600 x 400 resolution with 16M colors = (1600 * 400 * 2/8 which is 192000000 (greater than 1MB).",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "GENERAL Operating Systems",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following requires a device driver? (GATE CSE CS 2001)",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " Register",
        " Cache",
        " Main memory",
        " Disk"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "GENERAL Operating Systems",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},

{
    "question": "Which module gives control of the CPU to the process selected by the short-term scheduler?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " dispatcher",
        " interrupt",
        " scheduler",
        " none of the mentioned"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "CPU Scheduling",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},

{
    "question": "Which scheduling algorithm allocates the CPU first to the process that requests the CPU first?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " first-come, first-served scheduling",
        " shortest job scheduling",
        " priority scheduling",
        " none of the mentioned"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "CPU Scheduling",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},

{
    "question": " Which algorithm is defined in Time quantum?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " shortest job scheduling algorithm",
        " round robin scheduling algorithm",
        " priority scheduling algorithm",
        " multilevel queue scheduling algorithm"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "CPU Scheduling",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},

{
    "question": " Which one of the following can not be scheduled by the kernel?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " kernel level thread",
         "user level thread",
         "process",
         "none of the mentioned"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "User level threads are managed by thread library and the kernel is unaware of them.",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "CPU Scheduling",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},

{
    "question": "What is Address Binding?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " going to an address in memory",
        " locating an address with the help of another address",
        " binding two addresses together to form a new address in a different memory space",
        " a mapping from one address space to another"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "Swapping Processes – 1",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},

{
    "question": "What is Dynamic loading?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " loading multiple routines dynamically",
        " loading a routine only when it is called",
        " loading multiple routines randomly",
        " none of the mentioned"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "Swapping Processes – 1",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},
{
    "question": " Which of the following is TRUE?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " Overlays are used to increase the size of physical memory",
        " Overlays are used to increase the logical address space",
        " When overlays are used, the size of a process is not limited to the size of the physical memory",
        " Overlays are used whenever the physical address space is smaller than the logical address space"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "NOT GIVEN",
    "subject": "Operating Systems",
    "topic": "Swapping Processes – 1",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
]